Alfred H. Barr, Jr. Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - U, V, W, 1957-1959; Ullman, Pierre (The Institute for Advanced Study) USIA (corresp. re.) Urban, Mrs., Albert Valentiner Memorial Exhibition (Byrnes, James B.; The North Carolina Museum of Art) Vassar College Venton, Mrs., Frederick Villalobos, Julio Vilato, Zavior M/M Village Voice visitors (Hentzen, A.) Vogue (memo re.) Vollmer, A. Walker Art Gallery (Scrutton, Hugh) Warburg, Edward M. Warner, Keith Washburn, Gordon B. (Carnegie Institute) Washington, The Institute of Contemporary Arts (Richman, Robert) Weidler, Charlotte Weinstein, Max Weintraub, William H. Wellesley College (Clapp, Margaret Taylor, Margaret N.) Weng, Siegfried R. (Evansville Museum of Arts and Sciences) Werner, Bruno E. (The German Embassy) White, Gabriel (The Arts Council of Great Britain) Whitney Museum (Arts Digest 1954 November 15 article re.) Wide Wide World (Jones, Eugene S.) Wildenstein, Georges (Gazette des Beaux Arts) Windfohr, Anne Burnett Winston, John (Peridot Gallery) Winston, Harry Lewis M/M Wolf, Emile E. Woodruff, Harry A. (corresp. re.) Worcester Art Museum (Rich, Daniel C.) Wright, Frank Lloyd Wright, G. E. File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.323 mf 2185:282)
  - X, Y, Z, 1956-1959; Yardney, Michel N. York (City of York Art Gallery) Zadok, Charles (incl. TLS) Zalstem-Zalessky, Mrs., Alexis Zerbe, Karl Zervos, Christian Zverev (Pohyola-Stamoglov, D.) Zwirner, Rudolf (Documenta) (Box 1, Folder 1.324 mf 2185:400)
  - Barr - Iceland, 1959-1962; Alcopley, L. Bjarnadttir, Mrs., Bjarnveig (Asgrimur Jnsson Gallery) Copley, Nina Tryggvadottir Johannesson, Porkell (The University of Iceland) Jonsdsttir, Selma (The National Gallery of Art in Iceland) Jnsson, Ragnar ("Kynning" Society) Penfield, James K. (American Embassy) Ptursson, Valtýr Snaevarr, Armann (The University of Iceland) Thorgrimsson, Gestur Warfield, Benjamin B. (American Embassy) File incl. clippings, translation of Reykjavik Daily"Morgunbladid" article 1961 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 1.325 mf 2185:435)
  - Barr - Summer 1962, Berker, Kikret Fletcher, John R. H. (W. E. Burnet & Co.) Schoneman, Ruth E. (The Art Institute of Chicago) Shaw, Elizabeth Soby, James Thrall File incl. clippings, AHB handwritten notes corresp. with Olive Bragazzi, Betsy Jones, Rona Kaplan, Dorothy Miller, Sarah Rubenstein, MSB (Box 1, Folder 1.326 mf 2185:588)
  - Barr - Summer 1963, Comit International d'Histoire de L'Art (membership list) Eddy, Paul Dawson (Adelphi College) Green, Andrew Wilson Sharp, Robert Shaw, Elizabeth Thaw, Eugene V. File incl. AHB handwriten notes, corresp. with William Burden, Rona Roob, Betsy Jones, MSB, outline (Box 1, Folder 1.327 mf 2185:690)
  - Barr - Summer 1964, Pozzati, Concetto Rewald, John File incl. AHB handwritten notes, corresp. with Rona Roob, Betsy Jones (Box 1, Folder 1.328 mf 2185:736)
  - Barr: Summer 1965/ Florida December 1965, File incl. correspondance with Amry Fera (Box 1, Folder 1.329 mf 2185:783)
  - A, 1960-1965; Aaron, May Todd Abbott, Jere Abrams, Harry N., Inc. (Fox, Milton S.) abominable snowman (clippings re.) Acheson, Irina (Pushkin State Museum of Fine Arts) Acoustiguide Associates (Burton, Val; Franc, Helen; Heil, Walter; M. H. de Young Memorial Museum) Ade, P. A. (Ausstellungsleitung München E. V. Haus der Kunst) Adler Conkright, Rachel (Hirschl & Adler Galleries, Inc.) Africa (South African National Gallery; incl. Copy of Africa 1961 address at The Columbia Associates; memo re: Finke interview, press release) American Institute of Architects Allan Gallery, The (Allan, Charles) Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Smith, Gordon M.) Aluminum Company of America (Hall, Arthur P.; "Alcoa Industrial Designer Award") Alexander, Marie Allen, Edna (incl. corresp. re: Braque) Allen, George Allers, Harry W. Alley, Ronald E. (corresp. re., c.v.) American Academy of Achievement (Peskin, Hy) American Academy in Rome (Kimball, Richard A.) American Arbitration Association (memo re.) American Association of Museums (Cummings, Clifton R.) American Committee on Italian Migration (del Drago, Anne-Marie) American Council of Learned Societies (Burkhardt, Frederick; incl. press release) American Physicians Art Association (invitation) Anders, Lilli (memos re.) Andrews, Wayne (Charles Scribner's Sons) Antonova, Irina Antwerp (Goris, Jan-Albert) Appelman, Morris (Bach, Otto Karl; The Denver Art Museum) Arb, Rene Artamonov, M. Architectural League of New York Argentine Consolate General (Morinigo, Marcos A.) Armstrong, Mrs., Hamilton Fish (incl. ALS) Arroyo, Anita Art Friend Association (Segui, Shinichi) Art International(Fitzsimmons, James) Artist-Craftsmen of New York, Inc. (Glover, R. Leigh) Arts Council of Great Britain (White, Gabriel) Arts(Brush, Joan) Art News(Hess, Thomas B.) Art Voices(Mellon, Charles H., III; Pease, Roland F., Jr.) Arthur, Paul (Canadian Art) Ascarelli, Gianni Ascoli, Mrs., Max Association for the Mentally Ill Children in Manhattan, Inc. Atlantic Monthly, The(Weeks, Edward) Australian Embassy auto safety (clippings) Azimut Gallery File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.330 mf 2185:838)
  - B, 1960-1965; Ballard (clipping) Barland, Hèlen Barnard College (Friedlander, Mrs., Jerome M., Jr.) Baltimore Museum of Art (Parkhurst, Charles; Rosenthal, Gertrude) Bardin, Ruth Jonas (incl. 2 b/w photographs of Jeanette Roman, Carmelite nun) Bareiss, Walter Baron, Ella (American Contemporary Art Gallery) Barr, Margaret Scolari Barry, Iris Bartos, Mrs., Armand (corresp. re.) Battcock, Gregory (E. P. Dutton & Co.) Bauhaus (corresp. re.) Bayerthal Beall, Lester Beavers, Robert B. A. (Deerfield Academy) Bedrossian, Nuvart (Wallkill Central School) Beer, F. F. Beiers, George Berenson, Ruth Bentivoglio, Mirella Berggruen, Heinz (Berggruen & Cie) Bergman, Charlotte (memo re.) Berlind, Mrs., Sam (Westchester County Olympic Committee) Bernheimer, Gladys L. Bernier, Rosamond (L'Oeil) Beyeler, E. (Galerie Beyeler) Biondi, Laurie Bibliography of the Museum Collections (1959 November 15) Birmingham Blake, Peter (The Architectural Forum) Bolker, Joseph R., M/M (Bright-Bilt Homes) Booth, Winifred Bonney, Thrèse (incl. copy of speech by Jean Auburttin) Bonnheim, Byron A. (Edward H. Weiss and Company) Bouchard, Thomas Bourgeois, Louise (memo re. "Sleeping Figure") Boys' Latin School Development Fund (Holloyday, Guy T. O.;Williams, Jack H.) Bradley, Harry Lynde Braddy, Julia Bragazzi, Olive (memo re.) Brandeis University (Gilbert, Creighton) Brandenburg, Arthur (Duke University) Bress, Mrs., Hyman Brock (memo re.) British Council, The Brody, Sidney Brooklyn College (Eisenstadt, A. S. ) Brown, J. Carter (National Gallery of Art) Bucarelli, Palma (incl. copy of "Contemporary Italian Lecture") Buchholz, Erich (TLS, TL not microfilmed) Budget Bundy Art Gallery (Carpenter, Harlow; inc. list of paintings and sculpture) Burck, Jacob (Chicago Sun Times; ALS) Burke, Mrs., Frances Burlington Magazine(Nicolson, Benedict) Bush, Butler, Reg (memo re.) Busch-Reisinger Museum of German Culture (Coolidge, John; Janson, Horst W.; Harvard University; Kennedy, Sargent; Kuhn, Charles L. ) Thompson, Colin (National Gallery of Scotland) File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.331 mf 2185:1242)
  - C, 1960-1965; Cahill, E. Holger (corresp. re.; incl. Grace Hartigan ALS) Calder, Alexander (ALS) Caldwell, William V. (incl. introduction to the manuscript "Visual Sequence Art") Carlisle, Olga (2 ALS) Carnegie Institute (von Groschwitz, Gustave) Carnegie International (Washburn, Gordon) Carp, Betty candidates Carr, Louis (directions to the Carr house) Carter, Mrs., John Caryb Casy, Marie (incl. 2. ALS) Castelli Gallery (incl. TL Dowling-AHB re: complaint against Castelli) Catlin, Stanton L. (Yale University Art Gallery) Catlin, Tod (ALS) Chabl, M. (TLS) Chagall, Marc (4 memos re: Chagall Windows) Chanin, Abe (corresp. re.) Charles, Barbara Cheek, Leslie., Jr. (Virginia Museum of Fine Arts) Churches of Christ, The National Council of the (Ritenour, S. T.; incl. a Proposal for a Center for Interfaith Research on Religious Architecture) Christian Action (Collins, L. John; incl. corresp. re: the International Exhibition of Contemporary Art) Christie's (memo re: catalogue) Church, Henry (list of works lent to MoMA by Church) Claflin, Agnes (corresp. re.) Clarke, Allan Hugh Clark, Kenneth (incl. copy of "Art and Society") Clert, Iris (Iris Clert Galerie; inlc. 2 ALS) Cleveland Center for the Arts (Fitzpatrick, G. W.) Cohan, Zara Cohen, Arthur A. (Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc.) Cohen, Helen (incl. 2 ALS) Colby College (Carpenter, James M.) Columbia Broadcasting Systems (incl. wall label text; Kuney, Jack; Penrose, Roland; Picasso, Pablo) Columbus Museum of Arts and Crafts (Cole, Frances M.) Cone sisters (Beresford, Patricia; The Bobbs-Merrill Co., Inc.) Connaissance des Arts (Spar, M. Francis) Conant, Howard (New York University) Cook, Mildred (incl. 2 ALS) Cooper Union Museum (du Pont, H. F.; Smith, Henry; incl. corresp. re: committee to save the Cooper Union Museum) Constable, W. G. CORE (Farmer, James) Coster, Charles Henry Crosby, John (The New York Herald Tribune) Cuba (press release) Cumming, Burton (New York Graphic Society) Cunningham, C. C. (Wadsworth Atheneum) File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.332 mf 2185:1242 mf 2186:5)
  - Colin, Ralph F., 1960-1967; File contains AHB-Colin correspondence Hope, Henry R. (Indiana University) Musicians Emergency Fund, inc. (Bates, Eve; Jaffe, Mrs., William B.) Peat, Wilbur D. (Art Association of Indianapolis) Rosenberg, Alexandre File incl., clippings, AHB handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 1.333 mf 2186:126)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom: Berlin, 1960; Aron, Raymond ("Situation of Democracy" paper 1960 June 16-22) Bieber, Marion Deutsches Reisebüro Dubois, Gisèle Haffner, Sebastian (interview) Jaffe, Irving Lasky, Melvin J. (interview with Willy Brandt) Nabokov, Nicolas Wacker, Jeanne Wulf, Joseph File incl. clippings, pamphlet from seminar on "Tradition and Modernity" 1960 June, press releases, press excerpts, petition, copy of Congress for Cultural Freedom News 1961 June-July, social program 1960 June 16-22 (Box 1, Folder 1.334 mf 2186:172)
  - Constatini, Egidio (Glass Sculpture), 1964-1965; Guggenheim, Peggy (incl. TLS) Hodsoll, Gloria Rockefeller, Nelson A. Selz, Peter Weintraub, Jacob D. (The J & B Weintraub Gallery) File incl. clippings,Sculpture in Vetro, IX Internazionale del Vetro d'Arte 1964 June-July, 17 b/w photographs; 7 with negatives (Box 1, Folder 1.335 mf 2186:258)
  - Cards: Christmas and New Years, 1965; Alsdorfs, James W. M/M Ankrum Gallery Beall, Lester M/M Dahl, Einar Damiano, Charles M/M Doane, Mary Goodfellow Domjan, Joseph Dubourg, Jacques Durand-Matthiesen, Jean-Pierre Ebert, Robert H. M/M (Harvard Medical School) Fuller, Richard and Betti Gerardia, Helen Gerlach, Kathryn and Gerhard Girard, An[dr] (original print) Harper, Bill, Louise and Paul Hartung, Hans Heller, Dorothy Heydenryk, Henry Javits, Jack M/M Karoff, Simone & Findlay, Wally Ketterer, Roman Norbert Klee, Paul Kotshík, Michael Kuvshinoff, Bertha and Nicholai Lacloche MacKendrick, Lilian Morgan, Willard M/M Morot-Sir, Edouard O'Connor, Francis Perls Galleries Peter Marks Gallery Putman, Wallace Roszak, Florance Sievan, Maurice Sihare, L. P. Sörenson, Christian M/M Spark, Victor D. M/M University of Texas Vereisky, Orest Walker, Hugh and Shirley Wall, Edward Wilder, Amos Wilson, Jane Ziegler, Rene and Maurice (Box 1, Folder 1.336 mf 2186:356)
  - D, 1960-1965; Dale Damiano, Charles (incl. 2 TLS) Dana, Richard H. Danes, Gibson A. (Yale University School of Art and Architecture) Davis, David (Foundation for Youth & Student Affairs; incl. ALS) Davis, James E. (corresp. re: Davis films bequest to MoMA; incl. 3 ALS) Delany, Edmund T. (Palmer, Serles, Delaney, Shaw & Pomeroy) De Long, Frances (incl. TLS) De Menil, Mrs., John Derain, Andr (incl. AHB introduction to exhibition, wall label text) Derbecq, Germaine (Galeria Lirolay) Derenberg, Walter J. (New York University School of Law) Dintenfass, Terry (Terry Dintenfass, Inc.) Dobell, Mrs., Peter (memo re.) Documenta and films (Nowotny, Karl-Heinz; Zwirner, Rudolf) Donson, Jerome A. (Office of Cultural Affairs) Dorcley, Roland (corresp. re.) Doren, Mark van (TLS) Dorazio, Piero (incl. Giuliana Romai ALS re: Balla) Douglas Gibbons - Holiday & Ives, Inc. (McCullough, Mrs., Frank) Dowling, Mrs., Walter (American Embassy, Germany) Downing, George E. (Brown University) Drew-Bear, Lotte (International Gallery, Inc.) Drexler, Arthur Dubinsky, Linda Duncan, David (corresp. re:Picasso's Picassos) Dunn International Exhibition (incl. list of paintings; Beaverbrook, M.; Richardson, John; Wardell, Michael) File incl. press releases, clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.337 mf 2186:462)
  - E, 1960-1965; East Side Gallery (Freeman, Mark) Eisenberg, Mrs., S. Eisendrath, Craig (corresp. re.) Eisenhart, Mrs., Luther P. Ekstrom, Parminia (ALS) Elkon, Robert (Robert Elkon Galery) Elmendorf, John van G. (press release; recommendations and evaluations) Emil, Allan (memo re.) English-Speaking Union Epstein, Mrs., Henry Erffa, Helmut von (Rutgers University) Erhard, Mr. Erpf (2 memos re.) Esman, Aaron H. Esquire(Hayes, Harold) Estorick, Eric European reaction to American art (Shaw, Elizabeth) American art in Europe (McCray, Porter) Executive Committee (agenda for 1961 September 22 meeting) (Box 1, Folder 1.338 mf 2186:462)
  - F, 1960-1965; Family of Man (Fiorillo, J.; The Protestant Council of the City of New York; Mayer, Grace; incl. 10 pg. description of Society of Family of Man; incl. corresp. re. exhibition) Farleigh-Dickinson University Farrell, Patric Faulkner, William (clipping re: Nobel Prize Award speech) Federal Advisory Council (copy of Smith, H. Alexander speech 1957 March 25) Feigen, Richard L. (Richard Feigen Gallery) Feininger, Mrs., Lyonel Ferber, Cornelia Fernández, Justino (Universidad Nacional de Mexico) Field, Mrs., Henry Films Finkelstein, Louis (The Jewish Theological Seminary of America) Finsthwait, Mrs., Robert A. (incl. 3 ALS) Fischbach, Mrs., H. Fletcher, E. H. (Price Waterhouse Peat & Co.) Flinker, Karl (Galerie Karl Flinker; ALS) Ford Foundation, The (Koch, Sigmund; Johnson, Ruth Carter; Lowry, W. McNeil; incl. corresp. re. 1965 Museum Curatorial Training; program; press release) Fort Worth (Amon C. Carter Foundation) Foster, Jeanne R. Fox, Milton S. (Harry N. Abrams, Inc.) Fox, Samuel V. Franc, Helen (memo re: future assignments of editorial consultant to the director) Frank, Myrtil M/M Frankfurter, Alfred (Art News) Franzen, Ulrich (Ulrich Franzen & Associates; Architects) Freed, Marcia (Dover Publications, Inc.) Freedberg, Sydney (Fogg Art Museum) Freedom of the Arts (McCray, Porter; incl. draft of bill, report, joint resolutions) Freeman, Richard B. (University of Kentucky) Friedman, B. H. (corresp. re.) Freindel, Bonnie (Skidmore College) Fry, Annette (New York Democratic State Committee) Fry, Edward F. (incl. ALS) Fry, Varion (International Rescue Committee) Fulbright program (Dept. of State press release) Funt, David File incl. clippings, b/w photograph (Box 1, Folder 1.339 mf 2186:683)
  - G, 1956; 1960-1965; Gabo, N. (TLS) Gage, Camilla (corresp. re.) Galler, Donald Ganz, Victor W. M/M Garber, David M. Garber, John M. Gardner, John H., Jr. (First Presbyterian Church) Garrick Theatre Gary, Dorothy Hales Geldzahler, Henry (The Metropolitan Museum of Art) Genauer, Emily (The New York Herald Tribune) Germany (Schaefer, H.) Gilbert, C. (Brandeis University) Gilcrease Institute (Forrest, James T.) Ginkel, H. P. Daniel van (Canadian World Exhibition Corporation) Giron, Robert (Palais des Beaux-Arts) Gnudi, Cesare (Twentieth Anniversary of the Resistance, Committee for the Celebration) Golding, John Goldfinger (memo re.) Gombrich, Ernest (The Warburg Institute) Gomis, Joaquin (incl. ALS) Goodell, Robert C. (The Foreign Service of the United States) Goodrich, Lloyd (incl. copy of Goodrich-Arts editor letter re: open letter to the President 1965 October 2) Goodwin, Philip L. (corresp. re.) Gordon, Irene (incl. c.v.) Gordon, Mrs., Milton A. (Citizens' Committee for Children of New York, Inc.) Gottlieb, Adolph (incl. ALS) Graf, Otto (University of Vienna) Grant, Michael (The Queen's University) Gray, Cleve Gres, Tana de Gámez (TLS) Gribaudo, Ezio (Edizioni d'Arte Fratelli Pozzo) Griffith, Richard (incl. Lincoln Kirstein corresp. re: proposed Eisenstein exhibition; 4 pg. Kirstein poem re: Eisenstein) Grigaut, Paul L. (Detroit Institute of Arts) Grohmann, Will Grolier Society, Inc. (Ferber, Stanley) Guggenheim Museum (Selz, Peter; incl. clippings, press releases) File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.340 mf 2186:875)
  - H, 1960-1965; Haas, Mrs., Walter Haftmann, Werner Hall, Donald Halpern, Nathan L. Halpert, Edith (The Downtown Gallerty) Hamilton, George Heard (Yale University) Hammacher, Abram (Rijksmuseum; incl. 2 ALS) Hammarskjöld competition (Nordenfalk, Carl; Nationalmuseum, Sweden) Harmon Foundation (Brown, Evelyn S.) d'Harnoncourt, Ren Harrison, Ellen (ALS) Hartley (corresp. re.) Hartmann, Kurt Hartmann, Fritz, Jr. Hartshorne, Charles (Emory University) Hartt, Frederick (Washington University) de Hauke, Csar M. Haupt, Ira M/M Havemeyer (memo re.) Haven, Kathleen Hawes, Marion E. (American Library Association) Hazard, Leland (Plate Glass Company) Hazen, Joseph H. Hentzen, Alfred Herald Tribune;Book Review(Doren, Irita Van; Rosenbaum, Belle) Hess, Hans (The City of York Art Gallery) Hess, Thomas B. (Art News) Highet, Gilbert Hillman, Alex L. Hirshhorn, Joseph H. Hirschland, F. H. Hitchcock, H. R. Hochberg, Milton Hochschild, Mrs., Harold (incl. 5 ALS) Hodes, Scott (Arvey, Hodes & Mantyband) Hodin, J. P. Hofer, Philip (Harvard University) Hoffman, Arnold (Mesabi Iron Company) Honikman, A. H. Hotaling, N. L. Houmère, Mrs., Walter Huston, John File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.341 mf 2186:1051)
  - I, 1960-1965; ICOM (Pirlot, M. C.; incl. minutes of 1965 September 22-24 committee meeting; list of participants) Interchurch Center (Harmon, Francis S.) International Association of Plastic Arts, Inc. International Design Conference in Aspen (Gurlburt, Allen F.; Look; incl. program schedule) International Institute of Arts and Letters (memo re.) Institute of International Education (Holland, Kenneth incl. preliminary agenda and agenda for Seminar on Arts in the Soviet Union Meeting 1960 October 3-4; preliminary list and list of participants) Institute of Modern Art (incl. press releases) Isham, Mrs., Heyward Israel (Kollek, Theodore; The Israel Museum) Italy (Box 1, Folder 1.342 mf 2186:1203)
  - J, 1960-1965; Jacobus, John M., Jr. (Princeton University) Jackson, Martha (Martha Jackson Gallery; ALS) Jaffe, William (Bentley, Warner, Haskins, John Wolford, Hicks, Orton H., Lathrop, Churchill P., Scotforf, John R., Jr. Incl. corresp. re: Hopkins Center, Dartmouth College; copy of Secondary School Letter 1962 May; minutes of the First Meeting of the Hopkins Center Art Advisory Group 1960 October 21) Jaffin, George M. James, Astrid James, Philip (2 ALS) James, Charles (3 ALS) Janis, Sidney (Sidney Janis Gallery) Jardot, M. (ALS) Javits, Jacob K. (incl. 2 TLS) Jelliffe, Mrs., Smith Ely Jette, Ellerton M/M Jewish Museum Symposium (Solomon, Alan R.; incl. agenda for Advisory Council 1964 December 2) Johansen, John MacL. Johnson, Philip (Philip Johnson Associates; incl. 2 ALS; 2 TLS) Johnston, Robert W. Jones, Judith Bailey (Alfred A. Knopf Incorporated) Jonsson, Ragner Josephson, Matthew Josten, Mrs., Werner E. del Junco, Emilio (Trabia - Morris Gallery) File incl. clippings; press releases (Box 1, Folder 1.343 mf 2186:1310)
  - K, 1960-1965; Kahnweiler, D. H. (corresp. re.) Kaplan, Mrs., Jacob M. (Henry Street Settlement) Karpel, Bernard (incl. proposal re: Donation of library research materials to foreign countries) Katz, Bertram (2 memos re.) Kaiser (The Jewish Museum; memo re.) Kennedy, Ruth (Smith College) Kennedy, Jacqueline (corresp. re: the John F. Kennedy Library) Kerr, Coe Ketterer, Roman Norbert (Stuttgarter Kunstkabinett) Keys Kiesler, Frederick (corresp re: Kiesler's Endless House) Kimball, Richard A. (The American Academy in Rome) Kislova, Lidiya D. (corresp. re.) Knopf, Alfred A., Inc. (Gervasi, Eugene; Jones, Judith B.) Koch, Richard H. (incl. 3 b/w photographs) Koenigs, Wilhelm Otto M/M (corresp. re.) Kollmar, Richard Kootz, Samuel M. (Kootz Gallery) Kornfeld (memo re.) Kosice, G. Kracauer, Siegfried Kramarsky, Mrs., Siegfried Kripke, Homer Kröller-Müller Museum (Joosten, E.) Kuebler, Paul C. Kuh, Katherine Kultermann, Udo (incl. TLS) File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.344 mf 2187:109)
  - L, 1960-1965; Lachman, Charles Lacks, S. J. Lambie, John Lamplighter, George (The Equitable Life Insurance Society) Langton, Basil Larsson, Ellery Lasker, Mrs., Albert D. Leavitt, Thomas W. (The Pasadena Art Museum) Leisure, Hoyt B. (Los Angeles County Museum) Leval, Mrs., Fernand Levine, Joseph E. (Embassy Pictures Corporation) Levitt, Mrs., Mortimer Levy, Julien Levy Park Committee (Ascoli, Mrs., Max; Deutsch, Richard; Levy, Adele R.; Venuta, Benay; incl. minutes from 1964 November 24 Executive Committee Meeting; agenda for 1963 October 31 meeting; fact sheet; Parks, Plans, People - A Prologue: A summary of the Community Planning, Participation and Thinking) Lewen, Si (corresp. re: George Grosz; incl. AHB annotated notes) Lewin, A. Liberman, Alexander Life Magazine Lilienthal, David E. (Development and Resources Corporation) Lindley, Mrs., Denver Lindon, Jacques (incl. TLS) Lipchitz, Jacques (corresp. re: dinner in honor of Lipchitz) list (clipping) Lock, Charles K. (Look Galleries) Loeb, John (corresp. re.) Lofting, Cintra W. (incl. c.v.) Look(Cowles, Cowles; Hurlburt, Allen F.; Willard, Charlotte) Lowe, Mrs., Maxine File incl. clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.345 mf 2187:188)